HARUNA ABDUL KAREEM

FRONTEND ENGINEER

CONTACT

+234 70 664 012 70

benzimakareem26@gmail.com



kokoblackdev.vercel.app



Lagos, Nigeria. Willing to Relocate

SKILLS

HTMI 5

CSS3/SCSS

JavaScript (ES6+)

TypeScript

FRAMEWORK & LIBRARIES

React.js, Next.js, Redux

Vue.js, Vuex, Pinia, Nuxt

Angular.js

GraphQI

Axios (Rest APIs)

UI FRAMEWORK & LIBRARIES

Tailwind

Chakra UI

Ant-Design

Styled-Components

PROFILE

Quality oriented professional with more than 4 years of experience and proven knowledge in website design and front-end engineering frameworks and technologies. Strong creative and analytical skills. Team player with an eye for detail. Aiming to leverage my skills to successfully fill the front-end engineering role at your company.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer

Groupify Jun 2022 - Now

• Solely responsible for developing the customer facing website which helped in establishing an online presence

- Integrated APIs for core user activities like member registration, KYC and payout/withdrawal
- · Optimized API calls by defining Fragments, composing Graphs and grouping multiple Queries into a single Query
- Refactored numerous modules of the WebApp by utilizing best practices, state, low coupling and high cohesion design patterns
- Developed the public sales page, member registration and other core user interface pages on the Web App by creating component variants

Frontend Engineer

TangerineAfrca

Mar 2020 - Jun 2022

- Participated and contributed in brainstorming sessions for application features
- Facilitated the integration of Mailgun and Netlify, created email template and wrote server less functions to send auto response emails and store submissions for lead generation
- Integrated third party APIs for BVN and selfie matching, this helped to improve customer Identity
- Implemented feature flags for removal of the specific features for targeted customers on The Tangerine Africa Platform
- Implemented UI designs and integrated APIs for the dashboard and website re-design, providing more accessibility for users
- Fixed unnecessary page reload for core components with global state management. This improved the performance and UX of the web application
- · Acted as the primary frontend engineer for the migration of existing users from the various Sub-Cos(Pension, Money, Insurance) onto The Tangerine Africa Platform
- · Participated in Sprint Demos, while making sure that all feedbacks from stake-holders are captured and resolved

HARUNA ABDUL KAREEM

FRONTEND ENGINEER

TESTING FRAMEWORKS

Jest

Cypress

Story Book

VERSION CONTROL

Git

Github

Gitlab

CONCEPTS

- Object oriented programming
- Responsive design
- · Mobile first approach
- E2E testing
- Agile methodology
- Atomic design pattern
- React design pattern

OTHERS

Sanity.io, Vercel, Netlify, Heroku, Figma

EDUCATION

B.S.C.(E.D), COMPUTER SCIENCE EDUCATION

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer (Contract)

Rizevo Dec 2019 - Feb 2020

- Standardized all output with responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy
- Architected the entire client-end for the Customer, Business and Admin modules of the Web-app
- Completed, deployed and set up CI/CD for all web modules using netlify and github.

Frontend Engineer (Intern)

HNG I8 (Zuri) Aug 2019 - Dec 2019

- Created User stories that helped enhance user experience.
- Teamed up with other frontend developers to create pixel perfect userinterface.
- Teamed up with designers to evaluate implementable designs with responsiveness.
- Teamed up with backend developers to implement seamless functionalities.

HARUNA ABDUL KAREEM

FRONTEND ENGINEER

TO WHOM IT MAY CONCERN,

I am tremendously excited at the thought of joining your company. My experience and skills in JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS and popular frameworks such as React.js, Next.js, Vue.js and Angular.js make me perfect for this role. I've worked in large development teams that have sharpened my technical skills, improved my communication, and made me understand what it takes to meet tight deadlines.

My keen interest in programming and design helps me find creative solutions to technical challenges and develop visually appealing websites. My extensive knowledge of technical standards helps me manage projects efficiently.

I am results-oriented, highly motivated, and always work to exceed standards and expectations. I thrive in a creative and progressive environment and always seek new ways to improve myself and my skill set. I believe I have the necessary experience and skills to produce exceptional results for your organization.

I am grateful for your time and consideration. I look forward to hearing from you soon to discuss this frontend developer role in more detail.

SINCERELY.

HARUNA ABDUL KAREEM